Guide to the Election Returns of Allegheny County, Pa. Records, 1926-1983 AIS.1965.10
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Election Returns of Allegheny County, Pa. Records
1926-1983
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Allegheny County (Pa.). Department of Elections
AIS.1965.10
11.25 Linear Feet (114 microfilm reels)
This collection includes the official return books for the general, municipal, and primary elections in Pittsburgh, Clairton, McKeesport, Duquesne, and other townships, boroughs, and school districts of Allegheny County, Pa., 1926-1983.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection includes four series. Series I and II contain the official return books for the general, municipal, and primary elections in Pittsburgh, Clairton, McKeesport, Duquesne, and other townships, boroughs, and school districts of Allegheny County, Pa., 1926-1983, not including the years 1937-1940.
National Election records include President. State election records include United States Senator, Governor, Lieutenant Governor, Secretary of Internal Affairs, Supreme Court Judge, Judge of Superior Court, Representatives in Congress, Senator in the General Assembly, and Representative in the General Assembly. Municipal election records include County Controller, Clerk of Courts, District Attorney, Director of the Poor, Judge of the Supreme Court, Judge of the Court of Common Pleas, County Treasurer, County Commissioner, Recorder of Deeds, Register of Wills and Ex Officio Clerk of The Orphans Clerk, Prothonotary, and Judges of County Court.
Series III consists of tabulations and summaries of primary and general elections from various years from 1939 to 1979. Series IV contains voter registration statistics, 1977-1983. All series are arranged by date.
Note: This collection was acquired in four parts, or accessions, and is divided into series according to the date it was acquired. The majority of these records have been microfilmed.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Accruals
Additional material received in August 1980 and September 1980.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Allegheny County, Pa., June 6, 1965.
Previous Citation
Election Returns of Allegheny County Records, 1926-1983, AIS.1965.10, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Allegheny County Voting Records, 1926-1969, AIS 65:10, Archives of Industrial Society, University of Pittsburgh Libraries, University of Pittsburgh.
Voters' lists; Local elections -- Pennsylvania -- Duquesne; Local elections -- Pennsylvania -- McKeesport; Local elections -- Pennsylvania -- Clairton; Local elections -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Government; Local elections -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Allegheny County (Pa.). Department of Elections
- 1965 Accession, 1926-1936; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Series I includes microfilmed records of election returns, 1926-1936. These records are part of the original accession, 1965.
  - 1926 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 1)
  - 1926-1927 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 2)
  - 1927-1928 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 3)
  - 1928 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 4)
  - 1928-1929 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 5)
  - 1929-1930 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 6)
  - 1931 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 7)
  - 1931-1932 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 8)
  - 1932 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 9)
  - 1932-1933 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 10)
  - 1933 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 11)
  - 1933-1934 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 12)
  - 1934-1935 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 13)
  - 1935 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 14)
  - 1935-1936 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 15)
  - 1936 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 16)
- 1970 Accession, 1941-1969; II.
  Series II contains microfilmed election returns, 1941-1969. These records were part of the 1970 accession.
  - November 4, 1941 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 1)
  - November 4, 1941 - May 19, 1942 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 2)
  - May 19, 1942 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 3)
  - May 19, 1942 - September 14, 1943 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 4)
  - September 14,1943 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 5-6)
  - September 14,1943 - November 2, 1943 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 7)
  - November 2, 1943 - April 25, 1944 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 8)
  - April 25, 1944 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 9)
  - April 25, 1944 - November 7, 1944 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Reel 10)
  - November 7, 1944 - June 19, 1945 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 11)
  - June 19, 1945 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 12)
  - June 19, 1945 - November 6, 1945 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 13)
  - November 6, 1945 - May 21, 1946 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 14)
  - May 21, 1946 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 15-16)
  - May 21, 1946 - September 9, 1947 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 17)
  - September 9, 1947 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 18-19)
  - September 9, 1947 - November 4, 1947 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 20)
  - November 4, 1947 - April 27, 1948 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 21)
  - April 27, 1948 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 22-23)
  - April 27, 1948 - September 13, 1949 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 24)
  - September 13, 1949 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 25-26)
  - November 8, 1949 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 27)
  - November 8, 1949 - May 16, 1950 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 28)
  - May 16, 1950 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 29)
  - May 16, 1950 - November 7, 1950 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 30)
  - November 7, 1950 - July 24, 1951 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 31)
  - July 24, 1951 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 32-33)
  - July 24, 1951 - November 6, 1951 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 34)
  - November 6, 1951 - April 22, 1952 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 35)
  - April 22, 1952 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 36-37)
  - April 22, 1952 - November 4, 1952 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 38)
  - May 19, 1953 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 39-40)
  - May 19, 1953 - November 3, 1953 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 41)
  - November 3, 1953 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 42)
  - May 18, 1954 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 43-44)
  - May 18, 1954 - November 2, 1954 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 45)
  - November 2, 1954 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 46)
  - May 17, 1955 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 47-48)
  - May 17, 1955 - November 8, 1955 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 49)
  - November 8, 1955 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 50)
  - November 8, 1955 - April 24, 1956 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 51)
  - April 24, 1956 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 52)
  - April 24, 1956 - November 6, 1956 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 53)
  - November 6, 1956 - May 21, 1957 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Reel 54)
  - May 21, 1957 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 55-56)
  - May 21, 1957 - November 5, 1957 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 57)
  - November 5, 1957 - May 20, 1958 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 58)
  - May 20, 1958 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 59-60)
  - May 20, 1958 - November 4, 1958 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 61)
  - November 4, 1958 - May 19, 1959 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 62)
  - May 19, 1959 - November 3, 1959 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 63)
  - November 3, 1959 - April 6, 1960 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 64)
  - April 26, 1960 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 65-66)
  - April 26, 1960 - November 8, 1960 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 67)
  - November 8, 1960 - May 16, 1961 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 68)
  - May 16, 1961 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 69-70)
  - May 16, 1961 - November 7, 1961 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 71)
  - November 7, 1961 - May 16, 1961 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 72)
  - May 16, 1962 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 73)
  - May 16, 1962 - May 21, 1963 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 74)
  - May 21, 1963 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 75)
  - May 21, 1963 - April 28, 1964 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 76)
  - April 28, 1964 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 77-78)
  - April 28, 1964 - May 18, 1965 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 79)
  - May 18, 1965 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 80-81)
  - May 18, 1965 - November 18, 1965 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 82)
  - Tabulations and Summaries, 1939-1979; III.
    Series III consists of tabulations and summaries of primary and general elections from various years from 1939 to 1979.
    - Primary, September 12, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Primary, September 9, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Primary, May 5, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Primary, September 14, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - General, November 2, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
    - General, November 3, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - General, November 2, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Primary, May 16, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Primary, July 24, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
    - General, November 6, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Primary, April 22, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - General, November 4, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Primary, May 19, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - General, November 3, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - General, November 2, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Primary, May 18, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Primary, May 17, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Municipal, November 8, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Primary, April 24, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - General, November 6, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Primary, May 21, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Municipal, November 5, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Primary, May 20, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - General, November 4, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Primary, May 19, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Municipal, November 3, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Primary, April 26, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - General, November 8, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Primary, May 16, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Municipal, November 7, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Primary, May 5, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - General, November 6, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Primary, May 21, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Primary, April 28, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - General, November 3, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Primary, May 18, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Municipal, November 2, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Primary, May 17, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - General, November 8, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Primary, May 16, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Municipal, November 7, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Primary, April 23, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - General, November 5, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Primary, May 20, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Municipal, November 4, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Primary, May 19, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - General, November 3, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Primary, May 18, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Municipal, November 2, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Primary, April 25, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 6-8)
    - General, November 1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - General, November 7, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Primary, May 1973 (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
    - Municipal, November 6, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Primary, May 21, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Municipal, November 4, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - General, November 5, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Primary, May 20, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Municipal, November 4, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Primary, April 27, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - General, November 2, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Primary, May 17, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Municipal, November 8, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Primary, May 16, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - General, November 7, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Municipal Primary, May 15, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - November 2, 1965 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 83)
  - November 2, 1965 - May 17, 1966 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 84)
  - May 17, 1966 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 85-86)
  - May 17, 1966 - May 16, 1967 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 87)
  - May 16, 1967 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 88)
  - May 16, 1967 - November 7, 1967 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 89)
  - November 7, 1967 - April 23, 1968 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 90)
  - April 23, 1968 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 91-92)
  - April 23, 1968 - May 20, 1969 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 93)
  - May 20, 1969 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 94-96)
  - May 20, 1969 - November4, 1969 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 97)
  - November 4, 1969 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Reel 98)
- Voter Registration Statistics, 1977-1983; IV.
  Series IV contains voter registration statistics, 1977-1983.
  - May and November, 1977 (Box 6, Volume 1)
  - May and November, 1978 (Box 6, Volume 2)
  - May, 1979 (Box 6, Volume 3)
  - November, 1979 (Box 6, Volume 4)
  - April and November, 1980 (Box 6, Volume 5)
  - May, 1981 (Box 6, Volume 6)
  - November, 1981 (Box 6, Volume 7)
  - November, 1982 (Box 6, Volume 8)
  - May and November, 1983 (Box 6, Volume 9)